Rev. Eric Tachie Yeboah.

Box KN 4249 Kaneshie

Tel: **0203006512** / 0553669670 Email: eric.tachie@gmail.com

Career Objective:

To be a Resourceful, Creative and Highly Productive Human Resources Practitioner for a thriving organization.

Qualifications:

MBA (HRM option)

• Central University, Ghana (2008 to 2010)

Post Graduate Certificate, Leadership, HR & Strategic Management

• Graduate Training Institute – July 2015

Post Graduate Professional Level Certificate

Institute of Human Resource Management Practitioners, Ghana (2003 to 2004)*

BSc. Administration (HRM option)

Central University; (1998 to 2002)

Diploma in Business Studies (Accounting option)

Accra Polytechnic; (1995 to 1997)

Senior Secondary School Certificate

Accra Academy (1992-1994)

Career Summary:

A resourceful, result driven and experienced HR practitioner with fourteen (14) years of practice spanning through all aspects of HR functions from recruitment to training, talent management, performance management to compensation and benefits.

I have had the opportunity to play key and strategic roles in various organizations including a multinational and in various positions such as an HR consultant, HR manager and HR Coordinator. Currently I hold the position of Group HR Manager at Emery Invest.

Work History

Role: Group HR Manager

17 Feb 2020 to Date

Employer: Emery Invest Key responsibilities:

- Responsible for driving strategic HR programs and initiatives that will achieve overall Emery Invest business objectives and support employee development and engagement.
- Provide professional HR advice to all levels of Emery Invest as organization by building tactical
 working relationships with Line Managers and staff to ensure strong employee relations and
 engagement.
- Champion and enforce Emery Invest Human Resource Policies and Procedures

- Focal contact as advisor and coach to the CEO on all related HR matters Performance management, workforce planning, Reward and Recognition, recruitment etc.
- Maintains in-depth knowledge of legal requirements and compliance ensuring all labour legislation and procedures are in compliance with Ghana Labour Act 2003 (Act 651) and internal policy compliance across all Emery Invest Subsidiaries.
- Drive overall business performance by supporting line Managers in the effective implement of our performance management policy, career planning, coaching and performance feedback.
- As the lead contact in the design of HR policies, processes and systems and to work with other subsidiary HR Managers within Emery Invest to identify opportunities for further enhancements of future HR and business initiatives.
- Participate in projects that may come up in the HR function.

Role: **Head, HR & Admin.**May 2016 - Dec 2019

Employer: Ideal Capital Partners Ltd
Summary of Role:

Acting as a strategic business partner to the Managing Director and working closely with Managers and employees of ICPL at all levels of the organization on Human Resources policies and programs and aligning actions and results to the business strategy. Some other key responsibilities include: supporting and providing training on performance management program, talent acquisition, managing the annual review and talent management processes, and providing coaching to managers.

Key Achievements:

- a. Strengthened the Performance Management System
- b. Operationalized and signed off a competitive and equitable internal pay salary structure leading to a reduction in grievance and a raise in job satisfaction.

Role: Head/Human Resources April 2014 – May 2016

Employer: Christian Community Microfinance Limited (CCML)
Key Responsibilities

- In consultation with the Managing Director, prepared and implemented annual HR strategic plans to support the overall strategic objective of the business
- Worked closely with senior and line managers, providing them with expert guidance, coaching and support on the full range of HR activities (including policies and procedures, terms and conditions of employment, absence management, restructuring of services, performance management, redundancy planning etc.in order to ensure a consistent and fair approach to people management throughout the organization.
- Managed the implementation of the Company's recruitment and selection policy, ensuring that recruitment practices were fair, consistent and in accordance with labour regulations and industry / international best practice
- Provide leadership to staff, ensuring that all staff are aware of and comply with Company's policies and procedures
- Managed staff inductions, probation and on-boarding in line with Company's policy.
- Provided report and analysis on key areas such as turnover, exit data, recruiting, etc.

- Acted as focal point for all staff enquiries regarding policies and procedures.
- Monitored and adviced on disciplinary and grievance matters in accordance with Company's policies and procedures
- Led the employee performance evaluation process and partnered with management to ensure that
 all employees are provided with clear, consistent and regular feedback on performance; provided
 performance improvement recommendations and/or training where growth opportunities exist for
 employees to develop additional job skills.

Some Achievements:

- a. Developed and implemented a robust performance management system (PMS). The implementation helped in defining and instituting a culture of accountability leading to an improved performance.
- b. Implementing the outcome of Employee Climate Survey, I developed and implemented an effective employee retention strategy leading to significant reduction in staff turnover.
- c. Championed the introduction of organizational restructuring process, redefined corporate structures to align with corporate strategy.

Role: Regional Manager/Coordinator. (Ashante & Brong Ahafo Regions)

Nov.2012- April 2014

Employer: **Vodafone Ghana. Key responsibilities:**

- Support staff engagement across the region; improve on operational efficiency to support the business achieve its regional targets, manage key regional projects and campaigns; deliver an engaged, motivated, informed and empowered regional team to deliver results.
- Ensure that regional staff are informed and updated on key business and organizational issues
- Responsible for Corporate Image Enhancement and ensuring the achievement of key corporate deliverables Health &Safety / Diversity &Inclusion /customer Excellence /speed to market.
- Ensuring compliance with Employee Relations policies and processes in respect of Disciplinary Management; Grievance Management; and Performance Improvement Plans.
- Effective Management of employee representatives-Unions to ensure industrial peace in the region
- Act as liaison between the Legal Dept and the courts, quasi-judicial bodies & security agencies in the Region.
- Support the regional execution of a performance management performance dialogue
- Creating and embedding a positive health and safety culture in the region through effective team management.
- Work closely with Heads of Departments at the Head Office to facilitate trainings on products, policies and processes to up-skill line Managers in effectively dealing with Employee Relations matters.

Role: HR Consultant, Business Partner Team (2009-2012)

Employer: Vodafone Ghana
Key Responsibilities:

- Member of the functional leadership team, contributing to the broader business and HR agenda.
- Provided strategic support in all business reorganization initiatives i.e.-redundancy etc
- Responsible for building influential and mutually respectful relationships with line managers within the Corporate Functions and Finance department.
- Diagnosis and analysis of issues within the business, providing objective challenge and engaging the appropriate Centre's of Expertise to ensure issue resolution.
- Worked in partnership with AskHR Unit to respond to queries where a specific functional knowledge is required or as a point of escalation. Deliver response within agreed SLA's
- Responsible for the interview and selection of roles at salary levels G/H in partnership with the leadership team. Use internal & external selection as key tool in the development of talent within the Business or Functional Unit.
- Enhancing people management capability through coaching and development of line managers, building skills, knowledge, competencies on all issues relating to people and the organization.

Role: <u>HR Manager.</u> (2006-2009)

Employer: Ghana Telecom Call Centre
Key Responsibilities:

- Building strong relationships with the Managers and staff of Line Managers. Areas of responsibility included employee relations, recruiting, performance management and retention.
- Designs and conduct new employee orientations. Responsible for payroll and salary issues.
- Administers and explain company benefits to employees.
- Chairing the Industrial Relations committee and acting as 'lead' on the development of employee relations processes and practices including a new labour relations strategy

Role: Human Resource Manager: March 2005- Dec. 2005

Employer: Latex Foam (Moon Beam)

Key Responsibilities

• Undertook comprehensive range of responsibilities including recruitment, orientation, regulatory compliance, policy and & procedures. Provided counseling to employees and conducted investigations to resolve employee conflicts, and maintained personnel records of employees

Role: Project Coordinator (March 2003 to Jan. 2005)

Employer: West Africa Dispute Resolution Centre-WADREC (An NGO sponsored by Action Aid).

Volunteerism:

Program: Azuza Street Project:Position: Project Coordinator

• Date: 2003 – 2010.

• Project Sponsor: Destiny Transformation Centre – Kaneshie, Zongo Junction

Trainings & Development Opportunities:

Course	Organizer	Date
Compensation and Benefits Administration	CITAM	April 2018
Investment in Excellence	Ideal Financial Holdings	Sept. 2016.
SPHR Certification, Leadership Seminar	Graduate Training Institute- GTI	2016
Balanced Scorecard Methodology (Strategic	Palladium Executing Strategy	April 23, 2015
Management)		Novotel, Accra.
People Manager Training	Vodafone Ghana	Feb. 2014.
Two-Day Refresher course on: Driving	Road Safety & Transportation	Feb. 4 th 2014
Management Science.	Consultancies Ltd.	
Effective Appraisal Skills for Managers;	Creative Media Consult (CBM)	Feb. 8 th 2008.
		Erata Hotel, Accra.
Labour Management Relations & Labour Act,	Ghana Employers' Association	Jan. 18 th 2008
2003 (Act 651)		
Team Leadership Training	Ernst & Young	June 26 to 27, 2007
Leading Empowered Teams for Service	Service Quality Institute (UK)	April 24, 2007
Quality		
Time Management Training. (Corporate	Ernst & Young	April 12 to 13, 2007.
Adventure)		

REFEREES:

Available on request